lawlessfrench.com 2019-12-20

# Privacy Policy - Lawless French

The **Lawless French Privacy Policy** has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as described in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read this privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how Lawless French collects, uses, protects or otherwise handles your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with the website.

### What personal information is collected from the people that visit this website?

You may be asked for your email address to help you with your experience.

### When is this information collected?

Your email address is requested when you register for the blog or forum, subscribe to a newsletter, or make a donation.

### How is your information used?

The information may be used in the following ways:

  * To send the newsletter.
  * To follow up after you post on the blog or forum or make a donation.

### How is your information protected?

This website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to the site as safe as possible. Malware scanning is done regularly.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

A variety of security measures are implemented when you enter, submit, or access your information to maintain the safety of your personal information. All transactions for products and services are processed through third-party services and are not stored or processed on the Lawless French server. 

### Does Lawless French use ‘cookies’?

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, they are also used to help understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables Lawless French to provide you with improved services. Lawless French also uses cookies to help compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that better site experiences and tools can be offered in the future.

**Lawless French uses cookies to:**

  * Keep track of advertisements.
  * Keep track of your log-in state.
  * Keep track of forum posts you have already seen.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies, some of the features that make your site experience more efficient may not function properly.

### Third-party disclosure

Lawless French does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your Personally Identifiable Information. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist in operating this website or serving users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. Lawless French may also release information when it’s release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### Third-party links

Lawless French includes or offers third-party products and services on the website. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. Lawless French therefore has no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, Lawless French seeks to protect the integrity of the site and welcomes any feedback about these sites.

### Google

Lawless French, along with third-party vendors such as Google, uses first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to the website.

### Rakuten

Lawless French is partnered with Rakuten Marketing, who may collect personal information when you interact with the site. The collection and use of this information is subject to [Rakuten’s privacy policy](https://rakutenmarketing.com/legal-notices/services-privacy-policy/).

**Opting out**

You can opt out of customized ads by visiting [Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

### California Online Privacy Protection Act

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require any person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting Personally Identifiable Information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals or companies with whom it is being shared. – See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

In accordance with CalOPPA, Lawless French agrees to the following:

  * Users can visit this site anonymously.
  * This privacy policy is linked on the home page.
  * The Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the home page.
  * You will be notified of any Privacy Policy changes on the Privacy Policy Page.
  * You can change your personal information by logging in to your account.

### How does the site handle Do Not Track signals?

Lawless French honors Do Not Track signals and Do Not Track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

### Does Lawless French allow third-party behavioral tracking?

Yes. [What does this mean?](http://www.knowonlineadvertising.com/targeting/behavioral-targeting/)

### COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under the age of 13 years old, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, United States’ consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

  * Lawless French does not specifically market to children under the age of 13 years old.
  * Lawless French does not let third parties, including ad networks or plug-ins, collect PII from children under 13.

### Fair Information Practices

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe. Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.

In accordance with Fair Information Practices, should a data breach occur Lawless French will notify you via email within 7 business days.

Lawless French also agrees to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### CAN-SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

Lawless French collects your email address in order to:

  * Send the newsletter.
  * Respond to questions, comments, and requests.
  * Follow up after donations.

In accordance with CANSPAM, Lawless French agrees to the following:

  * Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way.
  * Include the physical address of the business or site headquarters.
  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly.
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can follow the instructions at the bottom of each email and Lawless French will promptly remove you from all correspondence.

### Contact

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, you may contact me using the information below.

Laura K. Lawless  
LawlessFrench.com  
8345 NW 66th St., #4739  
Miami, FL 33166  USA

laura AT lawlessfrench DOT com

Last Edited on 19 December 2019
